（桐仁(きりひと)）
最高の仲間たちも 半刻(はんとき)後には…
Your best friends may,
in the next moment,
最大の敵となる
become your greatest enemies.
I figured you'd say that...
（千比路(ちひろ)）お前なら
そう言ってくれると思ったぜ
Onimaru Kunitsuna!
Bout 10
"Unyielding Feelings"
Odachi
Excuse me.
（咲(さき)）すみません
大太刀(おおだち)高の皆さんは…
Is this the Odachi High tent?
（礼奈(れいな)）うん？
The team's already gone over to the ring.
みんななら
もう会場に行っちゃいましたけど
Oh, I see.
（咲）そうですか…
あの…　もしかして
マネージャーさんですか？
Are you, by any chance, their manager?
No, no. This isn't baseball or soccer.
野球部やサッカー部じゃ
あるまいし—
Sumo teams don't normally
have a female manager.
相撲部に
女子マネとかいないでしょう 普通
Does that mean... I'm not normal?
私 普通じゃないんでしょうか…
（アナウンス）
まもなく 個人戦を開始します
The individual bouts are about to begin.
（アナウンス）
西 大太刀高校 小関(おぜき)君
On the west side, from
Odachi High School, Ozeki-kun.
The individual tournament...
（小関）個人戦トーナメント
上位３名には全国出場の権利
The top three get to go to nationals.
潮(うしお)は
絶対に そこに入らないといけない
Ushio has to make the podium.
I was planning on sacrificing my
own chances to give him a leg up.
俺は そのための
捨て石になるつもりだったのに…
But if I go deep into the tournament,
I might end up fighting him.
このままいけば
俺が 潮と当たる可能性も…
Captain, focus!
（桐仁）部長！　集中！
（小関）ハッ…
Spirit!
（審判）はっきよい！
（小関）ウッ…
I started too late!
（小関）立ち遅れた！　マズイ！
Oh, no!
（小関）ンッ！
（審判）西の勝ち
West side wins!
Honestly...
…たく
That was close.
（西郷）危なっかしいな
相手がチャンスに慌ててくれたから
良かったものの…
It's a good thing the
other dude got overexcited.
You wouldn't believe that guy had
just beaten Ishi High's Sanada.
（舟木）石(いし)高の真田(さなだ)に勝ったときの
気迫が 全然 感じられねえな
（柴木山(しばきやま)）仲間のためなら
闘志が湧くタイプなのかな？
He must get his fighting spirit
from supporting his team.
He's nice to a fault, that one.
（寺原(てらはら)）
根が優しすぎるんでしょうね
Maybe he was so focused
on the team tournament,
部長として 団体戦に集中してて
個人なんて考えてなかったのかも
he took his eye off the individual contest.
Whatever the case,
いずれにせよ—
you can't make it to nationals
running from your friends.
仲間との戦いを避けて
全国には行けん
（アナウンス）東 大太刀高校 潮君
On the east side, from
Odachi High, Ushio-kun.
Oh, there's the guy who's favorite to win.
（橋）
オッ！　来た来た　優勝大本命
Yeah, man. Now that Sada's out,
he's got this in the bag.
（舟木）つうか 沙田(さだ)いないんじゃ
ほぼ決まりだろう
There are a lot of concerns
with him right now.
意外と不安要素も多そうやね
Like his arm, you mean?
（榎木(えのき)）腕の具合か？
（咲）それもありますけど—
That's part of it, but more importantly,
can he stay focused after that slugfest?
あんだけの激闘の直後で
集中力を保ててるか…
Spirit!
（審判）はっきよい！
（柴木山）心配するだけ損だな
（寺原）ハハッ…
Looks like worrying would be a waste of time.
He looks ready to chew up and spit out
any opponent, teammate or otherwise.
（寺原）チームメートでも何でも
かみ殺さんばかりの勢いですね
（蛍(けい)）
ハッ…　僕らダチ高が相手でも—
Will he fight with such intensity
against us, too?
あんな殺気を
ぶつけてくるんですかね？
We were all fighting as one before.
さっきまで一緒に戦ってきたのに
仲間割れみたいで なんか…
It feels like we're enemies now.
（千比路）フゥ…
Being teammates doesn't mean
avoiding all conflict.
仲間であることと
なれ合うことは違うだろう
You step into the ring to face someone
you know has a dream like you,
互いに真剣な夢があって
譲れねえって知ってるからな
and you give him all you've got, because
that's what it means to be teammates.
仲間だからこそ
がっぷり 全力で ぶつかるんだよ
（千比路）
つうか お前らも力士ならよ
やってみてえとは思わねえの？
And if you call yourselves sumo wrestlers,
shouldn't you feel the same way?
I want to face him at his best.
（千比路）俺は ガチのあいつと
やりてえし 勝ちてえ
And I want to win.
On the west side, from Odachi
High School, Kunisaki-kun.
（アナウンス）
西 大太刀高校 國崎(くにさき)君
Spirit!
（審判）はっきよい！
（火ノ丸(ひのまる)）ハッ…
（沙田）アア…
（真田）ウソだろう…
Are you kidding me?
That nimble footwork...
（真田）
その よどみない足運びは 沙田の…
That's Sada's...
First Quarter Moon!
上弦の月！
（荒木(あらき)）あ… あの野郎…
（沙田）ハハハッ…　やるじゃん
That sonovabitch.
Not bad.
I'd get copying the Demon Wheel,
（金盛(かなもり)）鬼車(おにぐるま)なら分かる
だが それは
この大会で見ただけの技だろう
but this tournament was the first time
he'd even seen the First Quarter Moon.
（桐仁）成長が早いとか
そんな安い次元じゃない格闘センス
It's not just about picking up things fast.
His knack for combat goes way beyond that!
With Hinomaru in his current state,
he might just...
今の状態の火ノ丸だと
ヘタすると…
（千比路）感謝してるぜ
俺に相撲を教えてくれて
I'm grateful that you taught me
how to sumo wrestle.
おかげで俺は また強くなれた
Thanks to that, I've grown even stronger.
Next, I'm gonna beat you
次は お前を倒して
また１歩 最強へと近づいてやる
and get another step closer
to becoming the strongest fighter!
あっ 佑真(ゆうま)の番だ！
Yuma's bout is next!
Yuma-san, take this guy out!
佑真さん！
やっちゃってくださいよ！
（審判）はっきよい！
（佑真）おら！
Spirit!
Pushed out of bounds.
Gojo-kun, on the west side, wins.
（アナウンス）
突き出しで 西 五條(ごじょう)君の勝ち
You did it, Gojo-san!
（蛍）やりましたね 五條さん
（佑真）ああ
Yeah.
（佑真）次は いよいよ …だな
（小関）うん
I guess it's time, huh?
Yeah.
On the east side, from
Odachi High, Ushio-kun.
（アナウンス）東 大太刀高校 潮君
On the west side, from
Odachi High, Kunisaki-kun.
西 大太刀高校 國崎君
Both of them look deadly serious.
（蛍）
ホントに２人とも本気なんだ？
Who are we supposed to cheer for
at times like these?
（佑真）こういうとき
どっちを応援すりゃいいんだろうな
No one can decide which is worthier,
Ushio's dream or Kunisaki's dream.
（小関）潮の夢と 國崎の夢
どっちを尊重すべきかなんて
誰にも決められない
And if I keep winning,
I'll end up fighting whoever wins this.
そして 俺も このまま勝ち進めば
どちらかと戦うことになるんだ
Hands on the ground.
（審判）手をついて！
He's a different beast entirely when you
face him in the ring for an official bout.
やっぱり 違(ちげ)えな
公式戦の土俵で向かい合うと
You're incredible, Onimaru Kunitsuna!
最高だぜ　鬼丸国綱！
Spirit!
（審判）はっきよい！
（火ノ丸）ハッ…
（千比路）おら！
（真田）なっ！
（荒木）あれは 俺の—
That's my...
inner thigh counter!
カウンターの内股！
After that throw in the first bout...
１回戦の出し投げといい
なんてセンスだ
What ability he has!
He struck back!
張り返した！
He's only been going for grabs up till now.
今まで
組み技しか見せてなかったのに…
Who knows what's gonna happen next?
次の展開が読めない！
Maybe he modeled that
move on your Cannon Slap.
（真田）モデルは 金盛の大砲(おおづつ)かな
（金盛）ンンッ…
A voracious appetite for any and
all moves that'll help him win.
勝利のためなら
何でも取り込む雑食性
For Kunisaki-san, this tournament has
been a feast of powerhouse techniques.
國崎さんにしてみれば
この大会は—
強豪たちによる
技の見本市やったってわけか
He's absorbed techniques,
and his style is forever changing...
（桐仁）吸収し 変化し続ける
もはや 稽古場での彼とは別人だ
He's completely different
from how he was in training.
でも…
But...
（小関）それじゃダメだ 国崎
それじゃ潮には勝てない
That's not enough, Kunisaki.
You won't beat Ushio like that!
（金盛）
見よう見まねの出来じゃねえし
センスは認める
He isn't just imitating the moves,
so he definitely has skill.
But even so, his versions don't have
the same intensity as the originals.
ただ やはり どの技も
本家のキレには及ばねえな
事実 鬼丸の下半身は ブレてねえ
You can tell because Onimaru's
lower body has barely moved.
What would I do here?
俺なら どうする？
潮に 廻(まわ)しを与えず
あの低い潮に差し勝つには…
How would I take advantage of Ushio's stature
without letting him grab my mawashi belt?
“俺なら”？
I'd try...
Hey!
おい！
He's using a leg sweep now?!
今度は掛け突きかよ！
Hey, that's Yuma's! That's Yuma's special move!
それ 佑真の！　佑真のいいやつ！
All of these moves have been a distraction
to help keep my options open.
（千比路）
ここまでの攻めは 選択肢を
絞らせないための目くらまし
My real plan of attack...
本命は…
is this!
（千比路）これだ！
He's going for a tackle from there?
そこから 変則タックルだと！？
國崎さんの本当の武器は
この柔軟な発想力
Kunisaki-san's real weapon
is his ability to improvise.
（千比路）くそ！　この大会で
強くなったのは 俺だけじゃねえか
Damn.
I'm not the only who's gotten
stronger at this tournament, huh?
（火ノ丸）
千比路　まったく お前は…
いつもワシの発想の上を行く
Chihiro, good grief.
You always exceed my expectations.
You're not getting both hands
on my mawashi belt!
（千比路）両廻しは取らせねえ！
In order to counter your improvisation,
（火ノ丸）
お前の その自由な発想に
向き合う度に ワシも強くなれる
I'll have to get stronger!
下手(したて)ひねりと内無双(うちむそう)の合わせ！
A twisting underarm throw and
an inner thigh propping twist down!
鬼嵐(おにあらし)･払手(はらいて)！
Demon Storm Hand Sweep!
Demon
Storm
Hand
Sweep
Demon
Storm
Hand
Sweep
An inner thigh propping twist down?
（沙田）
内無双！　またシブい技を…
Another refined technique.
He took his cue from the outer thigh propping
twist down Chiharu used in the team bouts.
（荒木）あいつ…
チハルが団体戦でやった外無双(そとむそう)を
ヒントにしやがったな？
Damn.
（千比路）くそ…
何が いちばん悔しいって—
The most upsetting thing is,
I don't even feel all that bad that I lost.
いざ 負けてみたら そこまで
ショックじゃねえってことだ
I feel more excited than upset.
…つうか ショックどころか
ワクワクしちまってるぜ
I've still got a long way to go before
I become the strongest fighter!
最強への道は まだまだ遠いな
That gave me goosebumps.
武者震いがした
His mind's probably a mess right now.
（柴木山）今 彼は
戸惑っているかもしれないね
It's okay, son. You're a sumo wrestler, too.
（柴木山）
いいんだよ　君も力士なんだ
You can respect him outside the ring
土俵の外の尊敬心と
土俵の中の競争心は—
and still compete against him inside it.
同居していいんだ
（小関）俺も潮と戦いたい
I want to fight Ushio, too.
そして 勝ってみたい
And...
I want to try to win!
Please don't die on me until this is over.
もってくれよ 最後まで
（審判）はっきよい！
（蛍）ンンッ…
Spirit!
He knew it was coming.
（佑真）変化が読まれた
（小関）マズイ！
He's done for!
His first official win will have to wait.
（千比路）
公式戦 初勝利は お預けか
Nice fight, Mitsuhashi!
（小関）ナイスファイト 三ツ橋(みつはし)！
Damn, I wanted to win at least one bout
before we headed to nationals.
（蛍）くそ…　勝っておきたかった
全国に行く前に
How can I win at nationals
if I can't even win in Chiba?
千葉県で勝てないヤツが
全国で勝てるのかよ？
Do you still trust me?
（桐仁）
まだ俺のことを信じてくれるか？
（蛍）ハッ…
（桐仁）信じてくれるのなら—
Have faith in me, and at nationals,
全国では
必ず お前を勝たせてみせる
I promise you'll win.
I should be asking you that.
（蛍）こっちのセリフですよ
As our instructor, if you believe I can win,
監督が
僕の勝利を信じてくれるのなら—
I will follow you.
ついていきますとも
地獄の果てでも
To Hell and back.
Not so hesitant now, is he?
さっきまでの不調は何だったんだ？
Our captain's put his doubts behind him.
部長も吹っ切れたみたいだ
I need to catch up to
the rest of my team by nationals.
僕も 全国までに
みんなと同じ土俵に…
West side wins.
（審判）西の勝ち
（拍手）
（小関）フゥ…
I've made it all this way.
ついに ここまで来た
Fifth bout of the individual tournament.
（アナウンス）個人戦トーナメント
１回戦 第５試合
On the west side, from Odachi
High School, Ozeki-kun.
西 大太刀高校 小関君
On the east side, from Odachi
High School, Ushio-kun.
東 大太刀高校 潮君
Whoa, a bout between the captain
and vice-captain of the winning team!
（観客）おお！　団体戦優勝高校の
大将と副将の激突だ！
Who do you want to win, Professor?
（千比路）
ハカセは どっちを応援してんだ？
Hinomaru, right?
（千比路）やっぱ 火ノ丸か？
（桐仁）えっ？
You came to Dachi High
to help him win, after all.
だって お前—
火ノ丸を勝たせるために
ダチ高に来たんだろう？
Wouldn't it be a tad inconvenient
if the captain beat him here?
部長に勝ってもらっちゃ
困るんじゃねえの？
（桐仁）
ンッ…　まあ そうなんスけどね
I suppose you're right there.
But as your trainer,
I've watched you all sweat and toil.
俺だって 監督として
みんなの頑張りを見てきたんだ
I wouldn't want the captain to lose
for the sake of someone else.
部長に“負けてくれ”なんて
思えるわけねえよ
However...
（桐仁）ただ…
Tell everyone my arm's
not as bad as it looks.
（火ノ丸）みんなには この腕
軽傷ってことにしといてくれ
What?
（桐仁）なに？　他校には
もちろん知られたくねえが—
I understand not wanting
other schools to know,
仲間にも隠すのか？
but hiding it from your own team?
Of course.
（火ノ丸）当然じゃ
（桐仁）あっ…
（火ノ丸）まさか 肘が痛(いて)えから
手加減してくれとでも言うんか？
You want me to tell them to
go easy on me because my elbow hurts?
（桐仁）そうは言わねえが…
That's not what I meant.
But it'd be stupid to aggravate it
in a bout with a teammate.
仲間のせいで悪化でもしたら
それこそ バカだぜ
（火ノ丸）礼儀じゃ
（桐仁）うん？
Respect.
みんなにとっても 大事な勝負
全力で当たるのが—
This tournament's important to all of us.
Going all-out in a bout
is how I show respect to my team.
ワシなりの 仲間への礼儀じゃ
ちょっと あいつ…
部長にまで容赦しないの？
He's not going to let up,
even against the captain?
Seems like he's kicked
his intensity up a notch.
いつにも増して
気合い入ってますね
Yeah.
Ushio, I can never thank you enough
for what you've done for me.
潮…
お前には
いくら感謝しても し足りない
Because of you, my love
for sumo has intensified.
お前のおかげで
前より もっと相撲を好きになった
You opened my eyes to
the joy of having teammates.
お前が教えてくれたんだ
仲間がいる喜び
And to the joy of winning.
そして 勝利する喜び
But those feelings...
ただ その気持ちは…
are for outside this ring!
土俵の下に置いてきた！
A spider stance?
（千比路）平蜘蛛(ひらぐも)！
俺んときは やんなかったのに…
He didn't do that against me!
That's because he wasn't sure
what you were going to do.
國崎さんは 何をするか
分からない怖さがあるからね
These two are going to
tackle each other head-on.
この２人は
やっぱ 正面衝突でしょう
This is my last Inter High.
俺にとっては 最後のインターハイ
That means this will be my first
and last official bout against Ushio!
つまり これが
潮との最初で最後の公式戦
（審判）はっきよい！
Spirit!
（ぶつかり合う音）
（小関）ドリャー！
（荒木）オオッ…
（金盛）鬼丸の当たりを胸で止めた
He stopped Onimaru's
charge with his chest!
I deal with this every day in practice!
毎日の稽古で受けてんだ
負けるか！
That won't beat me!
もろ差しねらい！
鬼丸に下手を与えない気だ
A deep double underarm grip.
He doesn't want Onimaru's hands
to get lower than his own.
Hinomaru grabbed him back!
火ノ丸が 押っつけた！
His grip isn't as strong as it usually is.
（小関）いつもの潮の力じゃない
Is his arm actually busted up pretty bad?
もしかして その腕 ホントは
かなり痛めてるんじゃないのか？
If we continue the fight like this,
his arm will get...
（小関）
このまま続ければ 潮の腕が…
Captain, are you thinking
of going easy on me?
（火ノ丸）
部長！　またワシに遠慮するんか？
Do you really think that will make me happy?!
それで
ワシが喜ぶとでも思っとるんか！
He pushed him to the rope!
（蛍）あっという間に土俵際だ！
（千比路）どうしたんだよ 部長！
What's wrong, Captain?!
That's right.
そうだった
小関信也(しんや)としての個人戦で—
For Ozeki Shinya, there will never be
another match as important as this one!
これ以上に大事な試合は
後にも先にもないんだ！
This is my final!
俺には ここが決勝戦で 千秋楽！
My main event!
（橋）押し返した！
（礼奈）今度は おチビが土俵際！
He pushed him back!
Now the shorty's close to the edge!
オリャ！
He's pulling me down!
（小関）強引だ　決まらないよ！
I won't let you!
違う！　本命は…
No, his real intention was to...
He switched to underarm!
巻き替えか！
I won't let you!
（小関）させるか！
Onimaru isn't thrusting with his right arm.
（真田）鬼丸が右を差せない
（金盛）やはり あいつも右腕を…
He must have injured his arm, too.
You knew about his arm,
didn't you, Professor?
ハカセは知ってたんだよな？
火ノ丸の右腕のことを
If you'd known, how would you
have approached the bout?
國崎さんは
もし知ってたら どう戦ってた？
別に　部長と同じさ
I'd have done what the captain's doing now.
What intensity.
（真田）すごい気迫だ…
（金盛）いつもとは別人だな
He's turned into a different person.
The upper body and cardiovascular
work the professor got us to do
ハカセによる
上半身と心肺の強化が—
really complemented the captain's
characteristic lower body strength.
部長の持ち味である下半身の強さと
うまく かみ合ってる
今の部長は 確かに強い　ただ…
The captain's become very strong indeed.
But...
Hinomaru won't just let you
win because he's injured.
（千比路）ケガしてようが 簡単に
勝たせちゃくれねえよ 火ノ丸は
Ushio, you're...
（小関）潮 お前…
using your injured right arm!
痛めた右腕で…
I can't complain about it hurting.
（火ノ丸）
痛いなんて言ってられねえよ
あんたが相手なら なおさらな
Especially when I'm fighting you.
I had to fight alone in middle school.
中学のころは
ずっと１人で気張ってた
自分と世間に対して張り合ってた
I was fighting both myself and society.
誰の手も借りず 忠告も聞かず
I didn't accept any help or advice.
I thought no one would understand,
and I was fine with that.
誰もワシのことなんて
理解してはくれんじゃろうし—
それでもいいと思ってた
あの手作りの土俵を見るまでは
Until I saw that handmade sumo ring.
それまでは
自分より つらい境遇で—
Up to then, I thought there
could be no one practicing sumo
相撲を取ってるヤツなんて
いないとさえ思っとった
in harsher conditions than I had to endure.
For the first time, I felt
like I had a brother-in-arms.
でも 初めて
同志に出会えた気がしたんじゃ
My elbow hurts, but so what?
肘が痛え？　それが どうした！
I'm not going to show my captain
anything but my very best!
部長に
カッコ悪い所を見せてたまるかよ！
鬼車！
Demon Wheel!
Ushio's laying it all on
the line to win this fight.
ここまで
潮が全力を出してるのに…
俺は…
But I...
I haven't been doing the same!
俺は まだ出し切っていない！
Endure it!
耐えろ！
我慢比べだったら 潮に負けない！
If this is a battle of endurance,
I won't lose to Ushio!
それでこそ部長じゃ！
That's the captain I know!
To me, you're just like Kuze and Sada.
ワシは あんたのことを—
久世(くぜ)や沙田と同じように
ライバルじゃと思っとるんスから！
A rival in the ring!
（火ノ丸）オリャー！
Your grip's not tight enough!
引き付けが甘いよ！
Hinomaru!
火ノ丸！
（寺原）マズイぞ　今のつりで
火ノ丸の下手が一枚廻しに…
He's in trouble.
He only has a grip on one layer of
the mawashi belt because of that toss.
That'll make it harder to apply force.
あれじゃ 力がうまく伝わらない！
（金盛）鬼丸のヤツ
意地でも 寄りで勝つ気だ
Onimaru's trying to stand
his ground and push him out.
If he could do a throw, he could
get into a better position.
（沙田）ここで出し投げでも打てば
もっと いい体勢が作れるだろう
That's what I'd do.
俺だったら そうするけど…
But backing away isn't Ushio's style.
（沙田）そこで退(ひ)かないのが
潮君なんだよな
Ozeki's standing up straighter.
（舟木）小関の腰が上がってきた！
That half-pint still had
that much left in the tank?
（礼奈）
あのおチビに まだ そんな余力が…
What tank?
（小関）余力？　違う　全力だ
He's going full power.
He's planning on using
everything he has right here!
ここで 全て使い果たす気なんだ
Which means, if I survive this, he won't
have any strength left to fight back!
逆に ここをしのげば
潮に反撃する力はない！
Endure it!
耐えろ！
ここを耐えきれば 俺の勝ちだ！
If I survive this, I'll win!
すごい…
Incredible.
I know saying this might
get me yelled at, but...
こんなこと言ったら
怒られちゃうかもしれないけど—
It seems like they're both having fun.
なんだか ２人とも楽しそうだ
I don't think it's your imagination.
多分 気のせいじゃねえよ
They appear to be enjoying
each other's strength.
今の あの２人は
互いの強さが うれしいんだろう
I'm a little envious.
少し羨ましい
I wish I could've fought Hinomaru
in a serious bout like this one.
俺も あんなふうに 火ノ丸と
実戦で向かい合ってみたかった
This bout is incredible, no matter who wins!
（選手）もう どっちが勝っても
すげえよ この試合！
Keep it up, Ozeki!
（選手）小関！　頑張れ！
I feel like I'm going to stop breathing.
こっちの息が止まりそう…
Tough it out, both of you.
（咲）頑張れ ２人とも
（バトムンフ）フン…
ハァ…
That half rice-straw bale...
僅か俵半個分の段差が—
For sumo wrestlers,
力士にとっては—
なんと険しい ひと山か
it is a fearsome mountain!
Forced out of bounds.
Ushio-kun, on the east side, wins.
（アナウンス）
寄り切りで 東 潮君の勝ち
（礼奈たち）わあ〜！
（真田）
見事な意地の張り合いだったな
That was an impressive battle of wills.
（金盛）小関の腰も重かったが
何より 鬼丸の執念の勝利だろう
Ozeki held out well, but
Onimaru's tenacity won through.
You'll probably meet him in the final bout.
（真田）
お前 決勝で当たるんだろう？
（真田）勝てんの？
（金盛）勝つ！
Can you beat him?
Yeah!
（沙田）あ〜あ…　なんで
ケガなんかしちまったかな 俺
Why did I have to get injured?
My body's trembling.
体がうずく　早く稽古がしたいッス
I want to get back into training ASAP.
Whoa, the easygoing Sada wants to train?
おお！　あの沙田が…
Well, it's understandable,
after the bout we just watched.
まあ あんな試合を見せられりゃな
Man, I'm disappointed.
（小関）くそ…　悔しいよ
（火ノ丸）あっ…
I'm disappointed, but that
was the most fulfilling bout
悔しいけど こんなに
充実した試合 生まれて初めてだ
I've ever had!
Now, I'll use this disappointment
to spur me on at nationals.
あとは この悔しさを
全国大会に ぶつけるか
まだまだ強敵が残ってるけど—
There are a lot of strong
opponents standing in your way,
but I believe that you'll beat them all
and become the high school yokozuna!
お前なら きっと
優勝して 高校横綱に…
No, a professional yokozuna!
いや 大相撲の横綱になれるって
信じてるから
（小関）あっ！　そうだった！
（火ノ丸）うん？
Oh, right!
Is your right arm okay?
（小関）
お前 右腕は？　大丈夫なのか？
I got all excited and forgot about it!
俺も つい調子に乗って
攻めちゃったけど…
ハハハハッ…　土俵を出れば
また いつもの優しい部長だ
Outside the ring, he's the same
caring captain as he always was.
Good luck, Hinomaru.
（桐仁）頑張れよ 火ノ丸
We will now present the awards.
（アナウンス）
これより 表彰式を執り行います
The champion, from Odachi High School,
is Ushio Hinomaru-kun.
優勝 大太刀高校 潮火ノ丸君
In second place, from Ishigami
High School, Kanamori-kun.
２位 石神(いしがみ)高校 金盛君　３位…
In third place...
Congratulations, Ushio-kun.
おめでとう 潮君　全国で会おな
I'll see you at nationals.
（バトムンフ）フン…
Okay, everyone, group picture!
は〜い　みんな 並んで！
（桐仁）火ノ丸！
Hinomaru, this may have just
been a stop in the road for you,
お前にとっては 通過点だろうが
今くらいは笑ってもいいんだぞ
but you can still smile!
O-Okay.
（火ノ丸）お… おう…
Come on, guys! Smile!
（礼奈）
ほ〜ら 笑いなさいよ おチビも！
You too, shorty.
Say cheese!
（礼奈）じゃ いくよ！
I see. So "forced out of bounds"
means they're still holding the belt.
なるほど…
廻しを持ってると寄り切り…
Thanks for the explanation.
解説 助かる〜！
I still don't know a whole lot about sumo.
私 まだ相撲のこと
よく分かんなくてさ
The guys who tagged along with me were
no help at all, so I'm glad I asked you!
一緒に来たヤツらも使えないし
こっち来て正解！
アハハハッ…
楽しんでもらえて良かった
I'm glad you enjoyed the tournament.
あっ！　私も
さっきの佑真の試合 撮ってたんだ
I recorded Yuma's bout.
Squee! Yuma!
（礼奈）
ギャーッ！　佑真！　いけいけ！
Go! Go!
Oh, yes!
ウオーッ！　やったー！
You really enjoyed it.
（咲）
これは ちょっと…
Next Bout  "Barbecue"